[Music]
hi
and welcome back to the next how to
create
luxury ice cream videos we do these
videos
hopefully you can make them at home but
we also use ingredients that you can buy
straight in the shops so you don't have
to have specialist equipment like
sugar thermometers or all this other
kind of thing that you don't necessarily
have at home you can go to a local
supermarket buy the bits and then create
these
so today's flavor is gimme small
ben and jerry's flavor now i had this
when i was in
new york and it was nice it is a nice
ice cream
but there were a few things i personally
would have improved on which we're going
to
try and do today so what is gimme small
it's a toasted marshmallow ice cream
with
a cookie swirl a graham cracker swirl
and
some fudge flecks in it now they
are quite difficult things to swirl but
um we'll get to that in a bit
so if you're unsure what a s'more is
it's one of these
marshmallow chocolate graham cracker or
you know digestive biscuits if you're in
the uk
heated pushed together eaten gorgeous
so let's just get on and make this ice
cream so we're going to start
with all the ingredients listed below to
make this toasted marshmallow ice cream
this is a custard
base itself so it's a little bit
different to the eggless bases
so what you'll do is you'll put your
sugar and milk in
the pan on the cob and heat it slowly to
dissolve the sugar
in a vessel next to it or close to
have your egg yolks all ready to go
what you're going to do is when that
milk is up to temperature
you're going to start to decant into
your egg yolks whisking thoroughly
every single time you put some milk in
there you're tempering the eggs
essentially you're
starting to cook the eggs but you need
to make sure they don't scramble
so as you're heating those egg yolks
keep whisking them up
and then by the time you've used half
your milk mixture
put your egg yolk mixture back into the
pot and then turn the heat down to low
and just stir it nice and slow for
around
five to ten minutes it's not going to go
thick like a custard like a traditional
custard
but it is going to thicken up a little
bit so whilst that
is on the hob getting all nice and
toasty you need to actually toast
the marshmallows so as you can see here
i've put them in a little
ceramic pot i'm going to put them in the
oven and warm them up as it turns out
the ceramic pop was a pretty useless
idea so
just spread them out onto a baking tray
get them in the oven 150 175 degrees c
something like that
for about 10 minutes soften them right
up but you want to
burn the outside not blackened within an
inch of their lives but you really want
to get some color on there
so i started the process under the grill
and then finished off with
the kitchen torch as you can see here if
you use
a smaller marshmallow then you know do
it over the hob individually if you like
but that's one thing that was missing
from the original was it just wasn't
enough of the toasted marshmallow flavor
once your marshmallows are ready you
then need to remove
your custard base from the hob and put
it in a blender
into that blender you're going to put
all those really sticky marshmallows now
one bit of advice here which i
failed with massively is i let the
marshmallows cool down a little bit too
much
on the pan it was really difficult to
get them off and they stuck to
everything the utensils my fingers the
lid do you name it they stuck to it
so keep them nice and hot and then get
them into that mix and blend
blend well for about 30 seconds to a
minute on full power
get that base really mixed up and you'll
see the color change
and that's the effect of that burnt
marshmallow indoor custard base
once that's all blended up put it into a
container
and cover with cling film put that in
the fridge for
24 hours so overnight you want that
those flavors to come out you want that
marshmallow flavor to really absorb into
that custard so 24 hours
and you'll be ready to go so whilst your
base is in the fridge
you can get on now and start making
those swirls so graham crackers are
something we don't have in england at
all
you can't buy them you have to import
them and i'm just not gonna do that for
some biscuits
so what we have in england is as mary
berry likes to call the uk equivalent of
graham crackers
digestive biscuits
very similar texture apparently and
taste wise i think it's pretty close but
i know that
graham crackers can have you know honey
and kind of cinnamon flavors to them so
what we're going to do is blend those
with
some honey what you're going to do is
just
crush your graham crackers into a tub
a little bit of butter in with some
honey warm that on the hob
and then mix it together you're going to
be left with
a nice thick biscuit mix
that you'll store in the fridge until
ready next is the cookie swirl
so cookies is a big american thing in
england we love cookies as well we have
different types i'm sure
but what we used in this video
was maryland cookies
[Music]
did exactly the same thing with these we
took some of these cookies
we crushed them up into a bowl but
rather than mixing them with something
warm we just used what we had in
cupboard and that was
some of this which is modern
syrup this is a lovely moaning chocolate
syrup
it's got a very decadent consistency
taste
it's it's really really nice stuff so
again mix that all together until you've
got a nice
loose kind of mix of of the two and then
put it in a
container and put it in the fridge until
you're ready to use it
the last part of this ice cream that
you're going to need to prepare is the
fudge flakes
so i did have a look in the shops for
some fudge but
it seems to be a very difficult thing to
get hold of at the moment so
i just made some so i made this fudge
with
condensed milk and chocolate
simple as that i'll put the details in
the description below
once you heat all of this up in a double
boiler make sure the chocolate's
thoroughly melted and then pour it into
your container
line it with cling film or foil or
whatever you like
once it's in there let it go hard out
either out in the open or put it in
the fridge until you're ready to
actually cut it and prepare it
a few hours before doing this i took the
fudge out of the fridge which is where i
kept it
chopped a piece off and grated it into a
container and then
stored that in the freezer ready to go
and what that does is that just helps to
keep those
fudge flecks separated and they don't
help them
back together into one large lump so all
that's left to do now
is start making the ice cream
so take your ice cream base out the
fridge
as you can see from the consistency
because of the marshmallows
containing gelatin they've created a
very
thick base so make sure you give it a
really good stir to loosen it up
and combine that with your cream and
then put it in your machine
so once your ice cream is turned like i
said this took 20 minutes
to churn we're gonna put this in our
lovely decorated container
which my wife has done again
and we're going to load this up with the
various different bits
i've forgotten fudge
[Music]
so as i said we're going to load this up
into the tub and we're going to mix in
our
little fudge pieces and our two cookie
based
swirls and put it in the freezer for
about four or five hours but in reality
probably overnight
right so it's been 24 hours since we
made
this hello since we made this
give me s'mores ice cream it could be
small i should say
i want to just quickly catch up on the
original to try on this when i was in
the states it's not the flavor you can
get over in england
and that is the marshmallow flavour was
very very subtle
and as in it didn't really taste a lot
of marshmallow the ice cream
and the add-ins the sauces
really wasn't enough in there to even
notice
the nice little fudge pieces so but they
you know they were quite decent so um
that's that now another thing i want to
touch on
is the reduction of sugar in the base
now when you're melting the marshmallows
in 100 grams of marshmallows is about 71
grams of sugar so you'll need to
subtract that from the overall amount of
sugar you would normally put in an ice
cream base
because if you just increase the sugar
it's unlikely to freeze or it might
freeze might just take a long time
so that's something you need to consider
making any ice cream actually
so now we're just gonna take some of the
tub and see what it looks like
[Music]
i mean look at that now that is what you
call a
cookie swirl how does it taste
for a start it tastes like marshmallows
the actual ice cream base tastes a lot
like
burnt marshmallows but not overburned
enough burnt
so the actual base really really good
much improved over the original
and i mean i may have eaten the rest of
the cookie swells that were left in the
tub so i know what they taste like but
amazing it truly is
something spectacular if you've never
made burnt marshmallow ice cream
my word you gotta try it numbers-wise
let me just grab my phone it actually is
relatively cheap
so these are all england prices
the double cream half tubs pound sugar
90 grams 90 grams 7p milk 15p milk
powder 4p
marshmallows 50p the fudge 185.
now i made that you might be able to buy
some a bit cheaper but
the graham cracker swirl obviously
that's digestive biscuits most people
didn't even have digestive biscuits in
the house
just use those if not that little swell
cost 78 p and the cookie swell
52 that meant a total of 491
and that gives you two tubs for 491
so obviously ben and jerry's cost about
4.99 five pounds something like that
i mean if you order it from the takeaway
you know pizza places
nearly six quid but you can make this
nice and cheap
really good ice cream please please try
it let us know
what you think of it and if you do try
and make it send us some pictures as
well
anyway i hope you enjoyed this video and
thanks for watching